<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Hi. Hey. Hello.]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.daniellin.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.daniellin.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-09T20:32:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.daniellin.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Lin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Read The Source]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.daniellin.net/blog/2013/05/09/go-to-the-source/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T19:46:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.daniellin.net/blog/2013/05/09/go-to-the-source</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/TA1kG9A.jpg">
I&#8217;ve come to realize the marked difference that separates a good software engineer from a great engineer out of school, is their apititude and attitude towards reading source code. This applies whether you are a front end facing client developer or one working on large backend systems.</p>

<p>Over the course of the last year I&#8217;ve transitioned from Android application development to automated deployment and backend systems. Before, we had a 1 man operations team that couldn&#8217;t keep up with constant deployments, so a group of 3 engineers were brought together to setup multiple server environments and automate the code deployment process. We chose to use the opensource framework, Chef. Much to my chagrin, their documentation is either terrible or out of date. Luckily Chef is opensouce and all their code can be found on <a href="https://github.com/opscode/chef?source=c">GitHub</a>. This has been a lifesaver. Reading the source code along side their documentation helps vastly in understanding Chef&#8217;s custom DSL language. There are also a lot of places where the documentation fails to cover proper command line arguments or configuration settings. Chef isn&#8217;t alone in this failure. Before this I&#8217;ve found that Android&#8217;s developer pages also a field of uncertainty. Most open source or internal projects are just like this; best documentation practice often forgone for sprint features.</p>

<p>Next time you&#8217;re uncertain about some program&#8217;s behavior, don&#8217;t be so quick to ask, use the source. You&#8217;ll come away with a deeper understanding of the code you interact with on a day to day basis. It&#8217;ll allow you to patch, write plugins, and be more certain of upstream updates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to Basics]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.daniellin.net/blog/2013/02/18/back-to-basics/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T01:47:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.daniellin.net/blog/2013/02/18/back-to-basics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Blog Migration</h2>

<p>For 2013 I have transitioned my often neglected blog over from tumblr to self hosting on GitHub. For those that interested it is built on using the Octopress framework built on top of Jekyll. The move was mostly motivated by feeling that tumblr&#8217;s tools were not longform friendly, which I guess is not super popular these days anyways.</p>

<h2>Personal Migration</h2>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Many of which I hardly use or even look at.'>
Almost a year ago I moved from Virginia to California to start a new job; and 6 months before that I moved from Pittsburgh to Virginia to start my first job. From college up till now I&#8217;ve managed to steadily build up a collection of clothes, shoes, books, electronics, and a myriad of trinkets; Many of which I hardly use or even look at. Also in the cross country move, I chose to forgo the luxury of living in a larger single bedroom apartment for renting a room in a townhouse. This meant going from 1600 sq-ft. in Virginia to a &#8220;quaint&#8221; 100 sq-ft. room here in Mountain View.
</span></p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='So far some of the items I&#8217;ve parted with include a Xbox, camera, comic books, text books, regular books, pc parts, etc.'>
<img class="left" src="http://i.imgur.com/L0vFHGT.jpg" width="240" height="320" title="'My Bookshelf'" > I have no problem with living in a small space, but over time I&#8217;ve found that my consumerism over the years as become quite suffocating. Being in a small space with all your belongings had this effect on me; constantly nagging for my attention and feeling that I should be spending more and equal time on all the various hobbies I&#8217;ve been so apt at collecting. About 4 months ago that I began to notice how much of the cruft on my bookshelf I could live without. I started to sell and give away anything I can&#8217;t remember the last time seriously using; kind of like a really long drawn out garage sale. Most weekends I&#8217;ll pick an item or a category of item and try to get rid of it, usually via ebay, craigslist, or freecycle. So far some of the items I&#8217;ve parted with include a Xbox, camera, comic books, text books, regular books, pc parts, etc. Hardly ever worn shoes and clothes come next. It&#8217;s been a very liberating to walk away from many of the activities that these items represent and I do actually feel very much more at peace having started this process. Still a long way to go, but my goal is to take an <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sannah/sets/72157615361417368/">All I Own</a> photo this year.
</span></p>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested, this is all part of larger personal initiative toward simpler living that was jump started by my discovery of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Early-Retirement-Extreme-philosophical-independence/dp/145360121X">book</a> based on this <a href="http://earlyretirementextreme.com">blog</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
